espionage: n.  间谍活动
Lesson 9 Royal espionage
王室谍报活动
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What important thing did King Alfred learn when he penetrated the Danish camp of Guthrum？
阿尔弗雷德国王潜入到丹麦人古瑟罗姆营地得到什么重要信息?
Alfred the Great acted as his own spy,
阿尔弗雷德大帝曾亲自充当间谍.
minstrel: n.  中世纪的吟游歌手
visiting Danish camps disguised as a minstrel.
他扮作吟游歌手到丹麦军队的营地里侦察.
minstrel: n.  中世纪的吟游歌手
In those days wandering minstrels were welcome everywhere.
当时,浪迹天涯的吟游歌手到处受到欢迎,
harp: n.  坚琴
They were not fighting men,and their harp was their passport.
他们不是作战人员,竖琴就是他们的通行证.
ballad: n.  民歌
Alfred had learned many of their ballads in his youth ，
阿尔弗雷德年轻时学过许多民歌,
conjuring: n.  魔术
and could vary his programme with acrobatic tricks and simple conjuring.
并能穿插演一些杂技和小魔术使自己的节目多样化
Athelney: n.  阿塞尔纳（英国一个小岛）
While Alfred's little army slowly began to gather at Athelney,
当阿尔弗雷德人数不多的军队开始在阿塞尔纳慢慢集结时,
the king himself set out to penetrate the camp of Guthrum,
他亲自潜入古瑟罗姆--
the commander of the Danish invaders.
丹麦入侵司令官的营地.
Chippenham: n.  切本哈姆（英国一个城市）
These had settled down for the winter at Chippenham:thither Alfred went.
丹麦军已在切本哈姆扎下营准备过冬,阿尔弗雷德便来到此地.
He noticed at once that discipline was slack:
他马上发现丹麦军纪律松弛:
Dane: n.  丹麦人, conqueror: n.  征服者
the Danes had the selfconfidence of conquerors,
他们以征服者自居,
precaution: n.  预防，警惕
and their security precautions were casual.
安全措施马马虎虎.
proceeds: n.  所得
They lived well,on the proceeds of raids on neighbouring regions.
他们靠掠夺附近的地区的财物过着舒适的生活.
There they collected women as well as food and drink,
他们不仅搜刮吃喝,而且抢掠妇女,aa
and a life of ease had made them soft.
安逸的生活已使丹麦军队变得软弱无力.
Athelney: n.  阿塞尔纳（英国一个小岛）
Alfred stayed in the camp a week before he returned to Athelney.
阿尔弗雷德在敌营呆了一个星期后,回到了阿塞尔纳.
assemble: v.  集合
The force there assembled was trivial compared with the Danish horde.
他集结在那里的军队和丹麦大军相比是微不足道的
Dane: n.  丹麦人
But Alfred had deduced that the Danes were no longer fit for prolonged battle:
然而,阿尔弗雷德断定,丹麦人已不再适应持久的战争,
commissariat: n.  军粮供应
and that their commissariat had no organization,
他们的军需供应处于无组织状态,
but depended on irregular raids.
只是靠临时抢夺来维持.
So,faced with the Danish advance,
因此,面对丹麦人的进攻,
Alfred did not risk open battle but harried the enemy.
阿尔弗雷德没有贸然同敌人作战,而是骚扰敌人.
Dane: n.  丹麦人
He was constantly on the move,drawing the Danes after him.
他的部队不停地移动,牵着敌人的鼻子,让他们跟着他跑.
assail: v.  袭击
His patrols halted the raiding parties:hunger assailed the Danish army.
他派出巡逻队阻止敌人抢劫,因而饥饿威胁着丹麦军队.
skirmish: n.  小规模战斗
Now Alfred began a long series of skirmishes--
这时,阿尔弗雷德发起一连串小规模进攻,
Dane: n.  丹麦人
and within a month the Danes had surrendered.
结果不出一个月丹麦人就投降了.
espionage: n.  间谍活动, episode: n.  一个事件，片断, epic: n.  史诗
The episode could reasonably serve as a unique epic of royal espionage!
这一幕历史可以说是王室谍报活动中最精彩的篇章.